So what is the hypothesis-led approach to problem solving?
Well, by definition, it's asking you to have a hypothesis.
And it's taking a very structured approach
and asking you, when you define the problem upfront, to think about what is the hypothesis
you're trying to prove or disprove — and make some assertions about that.
Then, as you think about the prioritization and the structuring of the work,
it's around how you test those hypotheses to get to a better answer more quickly.
It's also an approach that is widely applicable
to a range of problems. It scales quite nicely.
And it doesn't assume a tremendous amount of expertise,
so a lot of folks can use it.
So let's think about an example of where the hypothesis-led approach may apply. If you're thinking
about making a big investment — perhaps even acquiring another company — that's a pretty broad question.
You may not have a tremendous amount of expertise, and you may not have access to a ton of data.
But it's a question with a very clear answer.
You either will invest or you won't invest.
You will acquire the company or you won't acquire the company.
And so, in that sense, being able to take that fundamental question
as your starting point — should you do this? —
and then think about how you structure that problem
and break it down into the component parts:
those are great examples of where the hypothesis-led approach can be really powerful.
What makes me really excited about the hypothesis-led approach
is that it provides a great structure to enable me
to be a more creative problem solver.
And so there's both the art and the science in terms of problem solving.
And the science in the hypothesis-led approach is around
thinking through, in a very structured way, how you take
a very large, complex, ambiguous, hard-to-define problem,
break it down into the component parts,
and ultimately get to an actionable recommendation.
The art in the process is really the creative element. And what I love is that creative tension
when you're debating how we really define the problem — is one version of the issue tree superior to another?
The hypothesis-led approach creates that structure to really enable
those creative collaborations — and that is really the power of the approach.